- 你算出来我们在哪里了吗  - 仪器还在受涡流影响
- You've calculated where we are?
- The instruments are still affected by turbulence.
但是我觉得这是1984年 伦敦
But I think it's 1984. London.
- 找到它了 - 博士 你去哪里
- Found it!
- Doctor, where are you going?
时间走廊  我想搞明白这一切是怎么回事
The Time Corridor. I want to
find out what all this is about.
这么大的疏忽
Such neglect.
百年前这个地方应该熙熙攘攘 热闹非凡
A hundred years ago, this place would've been bustling with activity.
如果我们能找出是谁在操纵时光走廊 它就有可能又变成那样
It might be again, if we find out
who's operating the Time Corridor.
得，Tegen你的问题是，你没有想象力
Come on. The trouble with you, Tegen,
is that you have no imagination.
那是因为我不会为一堆破败不堪的砖瓦而伤感!
Just because I can’t get worked up
about a load of crumbling brickwork!
- 别进来 战士们  - 什么
- Don't come in here. Soldiers!  - What?
- 他会没事的  - 你看他着装的风格
- He'll be all right.
- Look at the way he's dressed
他一定是从时间走廊下来的
He must have come down the Time Corridor.
-  你必须帮我   - 发生了什么事
- You've got to help me.
- What happened?
时间走廊在下一层 小心点儿
The Time Corridor's on the next level. Be careful.
很黑...是不是?
Dark...isn't it?
- 小心四周. - 我没看到Galloway的尸体.
- Look around.
- I can't see Galloway's body.
博士 你看
Look, Doctor.
子弹
Bullets.
- 新的弹壳 - 不太可能是外星人
- Recently fired. - Hardly alien.
为什么要宣告你是谁 嗯？
Why advertise who you are, huh?
Turlough人呢
Where's Turlough?
Turlough?
他去哪儿了
Where's he gone?
Turlough?
- 你听到了吗  - 没有 长官
- Did you hear that?  - No, sir.
我觉得我听到什么声音了
I thought I heard voices.
Turlough!
需要帮助吗 先生  这里是私人产业
May I help you, gentlemen?
This is private property.
不好意思 我的一个朋友在这儿走失了
Yes, I'm sorry about this, this friend of mine
wandered in here by mistake
- 我们正在找他  - 我没看到人
- and we're looking for him.
- I haven't seen him.
- 发生什么事了  - 确切的说我也正想搞明白
- What's going on?
- Precisely what I'm trying to find out.
- 谁在那儿  - 请不要伤害她 拜托
- Who's there?
- Don't harm her, please! please!
- 她是朋友  - 对不起 博士
- She's a friend.  - Sorry, Doctor.
- 看   - 那是什么
- Look!  - What is it?
是个Dalek！快躲起来
A Dalek! Take cover!
消灭 消灭 消灭!
Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate!
消灭
Exterminate!
戴立克的复兴
(Whopix粉丝剪辑版)
- 他们从哪儿冒出来的 - 时间走廊
- Where did they come from?
- The Time Corridor.
- 从你之前所在的船上？  - 肯定是
- From the ship you were on?  - Must be.
- 他们想怎么样 - 我期望我们永远不知道
- What do they want?
- I hope we never find out.
瞄准那圆顶上的目镜
Aim for the eyepiece on the dome.
视力受损 我看不到了
My vision is impaired, I cannot see.
My vision is impaired. I cannot see.
- 快点  - 我看不到了
- Quickly!  - I cannot see
我看不到了 警告  警告 我的视力受损了
I cannot see. Warning!  Warning!
My vision is impaired.
- 把门打开 - 我看不到 我看不到
- Open the door!
- I cannot see!  I cannot see !
警告 紧急情况
Warning  Emergency
她没事 我们应该带她到楼下
She's all right. We should get her downstairs.
你去做那个 我需要人手帮我处理外面的Dalek碎片
While you're doing that,
I'd like a hand with the debris outside.
派去仓库的Dalek 被毁灭了
The Dalek sent to the warehouse has been destroyed.
那怎么可能
How is that possible?
博士有地球上的士兵帮助
The Doctor was aided by the Earth soldiers.
封锁时光走廊的在仓库的出入口
Seal the warehouse terminal of the Time Corridor.
- 她怎么样了 - 她睡得很自然
- How is she? - She's sleeping naturally.
- 喝茶吗 先生  - 谢谢
- Tea, sir?   - Thank you.
是谁找到这些圆柱的
Who discovered these cylinders?
施工人员 他们当时在把这个仓库改造成公寓
Builders converting the warehouse into flats.
我想这是尚未爆炸的炸弹
Thought they were unexploded bombs.
- 你有试过打开一个看看吗 - 连外壳都没划伤过
- Have you tried to open one?
- Haven't even scratched the casing
你觉得那些 Dalek 跟这个有关系？
You think the Daleks anything to do with this?
如果说跟他们没关系 那也太巧了
It would be an enormous coincidence if they didn't.
(space station Cassius Four)
(卡修斯四号空间站)
- 你要服役多久  - 两年
- How long is your tour of duty?
- Two years.
队长通常允许新人们先融入
Captain normally allows new arrivals to settle in,
再给他们分配看守的无聊差事
before subjecting them
to the tedium of Officer-of-the-Watch.
- 你做了什么  - 我投诉了
- What did you do? - I complained.
- 有人警告过你吗  - 我有这个权利
- Someone should have warned you.
- I had every right.
你有看过防御系统的状态吗
Have you seen the state
of the defence system?
- 你怕被袭击  - 重点不是那个
- You fear attack?
- That's not the point.
喔 我可不担心 在这周围我看到的唯一船只是我们的供给船
Oh, I wouldn't worry about it.
The only ship we ever see around here is our supply vessel.
我想，或许你过早下结论了
I think you may have spoken too soon.
感应器发现一艘有曲速驱动的飞船刚刚进了禁区
Sensors have picked up a ship with warp drive
just entered the exclusion zone.
-  通知队长  - 我不会打扰他 暂时不要
- Inform the captain.
- I wouldn't bother him. Not yet.
这有可能是任何东西 让战士们先检查一下
It could be anything.
Let the fighters check it out first.
他们会很乐意实践的
They'll be grateful for the practice!
检查完毕 所有系统工作正常
Checklist completed, all systems functioning.
竖起力场护盾
Raise the force shield.
所有部队到战斗岗位
All troopers to battle stations.
以战争速度行进
Battle speed!
士兵领队打开了视频 是艘巡航战舰
Fighter leader has made visual contact.
It's a battle cruiser!
升级到红色警报 快通知队长
Go to red alert. Inform the captain.
感应器报告说我们正在被扫描 长官
Sensors report we're being scanned, sir.
立即开启红色警报
Red alert at once!
我们被打中了
We've been hit!
- 发生了什么事？  - 工程部报告情况…
- What's happening?
- Engineering report...
-  怎么了  - 发电厂被破坏了
- What's happening?
- Damage to the generating plant.
长官 战舰正在靠进
Cruiser's closing in, sir.
我跟战士们失联了
I've lost contact with the fighters.
开火
Open fire!
我说了快开火！
I said open fire!
我做不到
I can't!
我们没有足够的能量使用激光炮 我们毫无防御了
We don't have enough power
for the laser cannon. We're defenceless!
- 战舰准备停靠了  - 哪个气闸
- Cruiser preparing to dock.
- Which airlock?
3号 维护队已经在处理了
Three. Maintenance team's working on it.
我希望所有人都下去那里
I want every available man down there.
用能找到的所有东西堵住走廊
Block the corridor with anything they can find.
- 他们停稳还要多久  - 3分钟
- How long before they dock?
- Three minutes.
- 我们最好去气闸那里  - 好吧
- We'd better go down to the airlock.
- Right.
一旦他们登舰 立刻毁掉犯人
Should we be boarded, destroy the prisoner.
祝你好运
Good luck.
0-3呼叫总部 0-3呼叫总部 结束
0-3 to HQ? 0-3 to HQ? Over.
- 一直试 别停 - 你必须要得到增援
- Keep trying.
- You must get reinforcements.
我不能把他们从空气中变出来 我需要一部电话
I can't conjure them out of the air.
I need a telephone.
- 我去吧 你在这里还有用 - 现在这不仅仅是军事问题了
- I'll go. You're needed here.
- It's more than a military matter now.
我必须跟国防部通话  我们需要大部队增援
I have to speak to the MOD.
We'll need massive troop involvement.
我跟你一起去
I'll come with you.
你是唯一一个知道怎么对付Dalek的人
You're the only one who knows
anything about fighting Daleks.
你守在这里
Your duty's here.
先生你 你们救了我
Gentlemen, you've saved my life.
我是Archer上校 服务于炸弹处理小队
I'm Colonel Archer, Bomb Disposal Squad.
我要打一个紧急电话 可以用你的无线电吗
I have to make an urgent call.
May I use your radio?
请给我
Please.
谢谢
Thank you.
它坏了
It's dead.
-  被袭击了 快撤退   - 快撤退 被袭击了
- Under attack! Withdraw!
- Withdraw! Under attack!
- 重建伍队 重建队伍
- Regroup! Regroup!
蠢人 我告诉过你们会有这情况，他们会在走廊里布雷的
Fools! I told you this would happen,
they'd mine the corridor!
攻击必须继续!
The attack must continue!
这次要按我的计划来
Only this time as I planned.
开火
Fire!
戴上面具 戴上面具
Masks down! Masks down!
移走它
Move it!
我们完了 每个人都保护好自己
We're finished. It's every man for himself!
毁灭犯人
Destroy the prisoner.
不起作用了
It's not working!
他是博士的同伴之一
He is a companion of the Doctor.
他应该被毁灭
He should be destroyed.
把他当作诱饵更好
He would be better used as bait.
博士敏感多情 而又易感情用事
The Doctor is sentimental and emotional.
他会来找这孩子的
He will come after the boy.
这有利于Dalek的计划
This will aid the Dalek plan.
让那个男孩四处游荡
Allow the boy to roam freely.
我们得回到 TARDIS，我必须要找到Dalek的飞船
We must get back to the TARDIS.
I have to find the Dalek ship.
我不去那里了 他们会杀了我的
I'm not going back there. They'll kill me.
- 我需要你来帮我 - 帮助？你不知道我胆子多小
- I need your help.
- Help? You don't know how much of a coward I am.
你正好可以抓住这个机会来展示一下 过来
You can take this opportunity to show me. Come along.
噢 就没一个东西能正常工作吗
Oh! Does nothing work properly?
试试这里
Try here!
这是什么味道
What's that smell?
激活通向时光走廊的出口
Activate the exit to the Time Corridor.
我们服从
We obey.
消灭 消灭
Exterminate! Exterminate!
Exterminate  Exterminate
消灭 消灭
Exterminate Exterminate
Exterminate  Exterminate
- 有枪声  - 快点儿 我们应该离开这里
- That was gunfire.
- Quickly! We should get out here.
快点儿
Quickly!
没什么好担心的 回去吧
There's nothing to worry about.
好了 炸药待发
Right, explosive charges primed.
那是什么味儿
What is that smell?
- 向后退 - 救救我
- Keep back. - Help me!
离我远点儿
Stay away!
我怎么了
What's happening to me?
不
No!
解除武装
Disarmed.
释放Davros
Release Davros.
那不是Archer上校
That's not Colonel Archer.
他把他的枪和腰带给了博士 但是这个还戴着
He gave the Doctor his gun belt,
yet he's wearing one.
你们俩在说什么悄悄话呢
What are you two whispering about?
我在想Tegen的救护车什么时候来
I was wondering when will
the ambulance for Tegen would arrive?
- 一会儿就到  - 增援人员呢
- That is in hand.  - The reinforcements?
这是军事问题，所以得保密
That is a military matter
and therefore confidential.
我想我们不应该再等救护车了
I don't think we should
wait for the ambulance.
仓库处于军事管制中
This warehouse is under martial law.
试图离开会被枪决
Attempt to leave and I'll have you shot.
我在那里冻了九十年
Ninety years I was frozen in that.
九十年的 心烦意乱
Ninety years of mind-numbing boredom.
- 那时候你有意识吗  - 每一秒都有
- You were conscious?  - Every second.
地球上的那些生物 没兴趣对人执行死刑
The creatures of Earth have no
stomach for judicial murder.
他们更喜欢让你 慢慢腐烂直到死去
They prefer to leave you to slowly rot and die.
这就是他们所谓的人道主义
They call it being humane.
那你也以其人之道还治其人之身
Then you must be equally humane in your revenge.
那是一个我应该毁灭的星球 被我优哉游哉地毁灭
It is a planet I shall destroy at my leisure.
但是首先 我必须要对付一个爱管闲事的时间领主
But first, I must deal with a meddling Time Lord.
- 这我们预料到了  - 你抓到了博士
- That's been anticipated.
- You have the Doctor?
分分钟的事儿
His capture is imminent.
就是它了 我已经锁定了Dalek的飞船
That's it. I've located the Dalek ship.
等到了仓库我接到Tegan就放你下去
I'll drop you off at the warehouse
when I collect Tegan.
- 我跟你一起去 - 你真好人
- I'll come with you. - Good man.
博士的Tardis 已经被带到时光走廊里了
The Doctor's Tardis has been
caught in the Time Corridor.
- 准备复制车间 - 遵命
- Prepare the duplication room. - I obey.
Turlough
Turlough?
傻孩子...嘘!
Foolish boy...Shh!
快点儿! 我们离开这里吧
Quickly! Let's get out of here.
不, 博士
No, Doctor.
真是疯了
This is madness.
Dalek不会因为感谢你抓住了我 它们会杀了你
The Daleks won't thank you
for capturing me. They'll kill you.
我没有完全说实话
I didn't quite tell the truth.
我服务于Dalek 我是它们的特工
I serve the Daleks. I'm a Dalek agent.
消灭博士 消灭博士
Exterminate the Doctor!
- 消... - 等等
- Exterm... - Wait!
他是Dalek的敌人 他必须被消灭
He is an enemy of the Daleks.
He must be exterminated.
他必须先被复制
He must be duplicated first.
请跟Dalek元首联系
Confirm with the Supreme Dalek.
Dalek元首确认了这项命令
Supreme Dalek confirms the order.
我们必须把俘虏 送到复制室
We must take the prisoner to the duplication chamber.
向前走
Proceed.
- 他们很冲动 不是吗 - 他们会杀了任何人
- Impulsive, aren't they?
- They'd kill anybody,
就算他们需要他
even if they need them.
什么时候轮到你呢
How long before it's your turn
蹲下!
Down!
开火!
Fire!
小心点儿.
Careful.
穿上他们的制服!
Uniforms!
穿上他们的制服
Uniforms.
我们应该马上离开这儿
We should leave here at once.
没Davros,我们没有未来
Without Davros, we have no future.
我们一定要让他相信 我们服务于他
He must be made to believe that we serve him.
Dalek和Movellan陷入了僵局
The Daleks and the Movellans
were locked in an impasse.
每次他们各自的舰队试图施行一个策略,
Each time their respective fleets
attempted a stratagem,
都会被对方的战争电脑立即识破和进行反击
it was instantly anticipated and countered
by their opponent's battle computer.
后来 Movellan 找到了制胜先机
Then the Movellans found the answer.
对不起, 先生
Sorry, sir.
快点, 告诉我
Quickly, tell me.
他们发明了一种专门对付Dalek的病毒
They developed a virus which exclusively attacks the Daleks.
整个舰队都被摧毁了 幸存的都逃走到了宇宙的各个地方
The fleet was destroyed. Those who survived
went to separate parts of the Universe
为了避免进一步感染，也为了寻找治愈方法
to avoid the risk of further
infection and to work on a cure.
- 找到了吗  - 还没有
- Have they succeeded?  - Not yet.
你们要拿要我的复制品干什么
What would do you with my duplicate?
- 那与你无关  - 我觉得有关我可相当喜欢自己
- That does not concern you.
- Oh, I think it does. I'm rather attached to myself.
你要保持沉默
You will remain silent.
我猜我的脑电波会被传送给Davros
I assume my brain waves are destined for Davros.
你们一定十分需要他
You must need his services very badly.
Dalek是高等种族 我们不需要帮助
Daleks are the superior being.
We do not require assistance.
高等 你花了一辈子时间把Tardis引入时间走廊吧
Superior? It took you long enough
to ensure the Tardis in the Time Corridor.
- 只是一个陷阱 - 嗯 Stien看起来更有效率
- It was but one trap.
- Hm. Stien was more effective.
一个活生生有思想的人 而不是一部铁锅机器
A living, thinking being, not some tin-pot machine.
- 别说了 博士  - Stien只是Dalek技术的一个延伸
- Please, Doctor!
- Stien is but an extension of Dalek technology.
- 什么 - 他是个复制品
- What? - He is a duplicate.
他是 我们基因工程的产物
He is a product of our genetic engineering.
- 你们所有人都是复制品吗 - 是的
- Are you all duplicates? - Yes.
真有意思 我想知道你们本人身上发生了些什么
Interesting. I wonder what happened to the real you.
这很重要 你早点完成你的研究
It is vital you complete
your researches as soon as possible.
- 我需要Movellan病毒的样本 - 等一下会拿给你
- I need a sample of the Movellan virus.
- It will be brought to you.
我还需要两个Dalek
I will also need two Daleks
来做实验
for experimentation.
那不行
That is forbidden.
如果要我找到解药 我需要活体Dalek组织
If I am to find a cure,
I will need living Dalek tissue.
- 我们必须要问过Dalek元首 - 那就去问 快点
- We must consult the Supreme Dalek.
- Do so! But be quick!
自毁系统控制室 被入侵了
The self-destruct chamber has been invaded.
敌人必须被消灭
The hostiles must be exterminated.
没时间了 放弃空间站
There isn't time. Abandon the space station.
你应该预料到这个
You should have anticipated this.
最初的计划是救出Davros然后离开 而不是跟着他的兴致跳舞
The original plan was to snatch Davros and leave, not dance to his every whim
不能让Davros有任何危险
Nothing must endanger Davros.
敌人必须被毁掉 必须要服从Dalek
The hostiles must be destroyed.
The Daleks must be obeyed!
外面  关上门  Dalek军队来了
That's outside! Close the door! Dalek troopers!
他们肯定看到我们了 端掉那个摄像头
They must have seen us. Take out that camera.
设个障碍物 可以用来保护我们
Build a barricade. Something we can use for protection.
- 仓库的士兵们已经被复制了吗 - 是的
- Have the soldiers from the warehouse
been duplicated?  - Yes.
真聪明 告诉我是怎么搞定的
It's very clever. Would you care to tell me how it's done.
- 不  - 我想你不会的
- No.  - Thought you wouldn't.
Tegan怎么办
What about Tegan?
- 她是我们的犯人 - 她不会害人 你们必须放了她
- She is our prisoner.
- She's harmless. You must release her.
给他看
Show him.
- 为什么 - 没有同伴的博士
- Why? - A Doctor with no companions
- 看起来一无是处 - 你为什么要这样做
- would be rather incongruous.
- Why are you doing this?
你的复制品会回到Gallifrey
Your duplicates will return to Gallifrey.
在我们的控制下 你要去刺杀 高等议会的成员
At our command, you will assassinate
the members of the High Council.
不
No!
我们是被  Dalek元首派来的
We have been sent by the Supreme Dalek.
我们要帮你完成试验
We are to assist in your research.
- 我需要的是Dalek组织,不是帮助 - 你可以从我们身上提取组织
- I need Dalek tissue, not help.
- You may remove tissue from us.
很好
Excellent.
我的实验绝不会有害
In no way will my experiment harm.
松开固定锁
Releasing locking clamp.
事实上你们会变得相当精神
In fact, you will become considerably invigorated.
太好了
Perfect.
重新封上你们的外壳
Reseal your casings.
现在....
Now....
你们服从谁
Who do you obey?
我们服从Davros 他是我们的主人
We obey Davros. He is our Master!
非常好
Excellent.
现在我需要的是Movellan病毒的样本
Now all I require is a sample of the Movellan virus.
命令他们把一个Movellan病毒的样本 从地球上传送过来
Order a cylinder of Movellan virus
to be transported from Earth.
遵命
I obey.
把收集器拿给Davros
Take the cylinder to Davros.
非常好
Perfect.
我还剩下一个请求
I have but one more request.
我希望我们能合作久一点
I require your co-operation a little longer.
这个反应很英勇也很愚蠢 他会成为一个非常好的奴隶
A spirited but foolish reaction.
He will make an excellent slave.
而你也会
And so will you.
- 你准备好了吗 - 你这样问好像我有得选一样
- Are you ready?
- You ask it as though I have a choice.
每个人都有选...择 这出自宪法 第25修正案 还是第26？
Everyone has a ch...oice. It's in the C-Constitution,
25th Amendment. Or is it the Twenty-Sixth?
- 你没有上过学吗  - 我那天肯定翘课了
- Didn't you go to school?
- I must have played truant that day.
也许我们上的不是同一所学校 你上的哪所学校
Maybe we didn't go to the same school.
Which school did you go to?
- 我 我不记得了 - 但你还记得一项修正案
-  I-I c-can't remember
- But you remember one of the Amendments!
怎么开始的 我知道那很重要
What was the First? It's very important that I know.
你能想起来 这也很重要
It's very important that you remember too.
想想 在你大脑中被Daleks 关闭的区域里寻找
Think! Search the area of your mind the Daleks has shut off.
抵制它 否则就太晚了
Resist before it's too late.
我必须继...续
I must cont...inue.
抵制
Resist!
我必须继...续
I must con...tinue.
（注：Nyssa：S18E07-S20E04）
（注：Brigadier(准将/旅长) Alistair Gordon Lethbridge-Stewart，UNIT 负责人）
放松, 博士. 不要抵抗. 你只会给自己带来...疼痛
Relax, Doctor. Don't fight it.
You'll only cause yourself...pain.
我-我了解你的感受, 疼痛会过去的, 你必须放松
I-I know you you feel.
The pain will pass. You must relax.
快
Quickly!
背诵修正案
Recite the Amendments!
（注：Adric：S18E03-S19E06 ）
- 我要尽责  - 你必须要抵抗
- I must do my duty.  - You must resist.
你要毁了我的大脑
You are destroying my mind.
站到一边
Stand by.
就是它了
That's it.
啊
Aaaagh!/
- 把他们送进时间走廊 - 啊
- Get them into the Time Corridor. - Aaagh!
不... 啊
No...! Aaaaaagh!
跟她一起进去时间走廊
Into the Time Corridor with her.
（注： Romana II 也是一位时间领主）
（注：Leela 第四任博士同伴）
（注：Sarah Jane Smith）
（注：Jo Grant 第三任博士同伴）
（注：Liz Shaw 第三任博士同伴）
（注：左二Zoe Heriot 第二任博士同伴 S05E07 - S06E07）
（注：左二Victoria Waterfield:
第二任博士同伴）
（注：右Jamie McCrimmon 第二任博士同伴）
（注：第二任博士 S04E03 -  S06E07）
（注：左Ben Jackson S03E10 - S04E08）
（注：左二Polly 第一、二任博士同伴）
（注：左一 第一任博士）
（注：左一 Sara Kingdom）
Dalek已经占领自毁控制室了 这里是安全的
The Daleks have secured the self-destruct
chamber. The statiom is safe.
很好
Excellent.
- Daleks 还把博士抓住了  - 这更好了
- The Daleks have taken the Doctor prisoner.
- Better still.
马上把他带到我这儿来 快点 我有非常重要的事情要做
He must be brought to me at once.
Hurry. There is important work to do.
这一刻我已经等了很久了
I have waited a long time for this.
- 你在干嘛  - 我怕她尖叫
- What are you doing?!
- She was about to scream.
- 这是Tegan 我的朋友  - Turlough... 他是谁
- It's Tegan. She's a friend.
- Turlough... Who's this?
别管这个了 我们得在Daleks到来之前离开这里
Never mind that. We must get away
before the Daleks arrive.
- 不跟博士一起吗 - 他在这儿吗
- Not without the Doctor.  - He's here?
在你后面
Look behind you.
（注：左二Steven Taylor
右一
The Daleks' Master Plan）
（注：左Steven Taylor
中Katarina
）
（注：左Steven Taylor
右Vicki
）
（注：左一Ian Chesterton
左二Barbara Wright
左三V？
）
（注：左一第一任博士
左二Barbara Wright
右Ian Chesterton）
（注：右Susan Foreman 博士的孙女）
脑子里好混乱 我受不鸟惹
I can't stand the confusion in my mind.
快点儿... 放了我
Quickly... Release me.
- 守卫怎么办 - 我们把他们引进这里来
- What about the guards?
- We'll call them in here.
你必须替我守着Tardis, 军队交给你了
You must secure the Tardis for me. Take the troopers.
遵命
We obey
快进来
In here!
现在怎么办? Dalek的控制随时可能屏蔽掉我的意识
Now what? Dalek conditioning
could c-cloud my mind at any time.
- 在Tardis里面你会很安全的 - 你没明白, 我可能会杀了你
- You'll be safe in the Tardis.
- You don't understand. I could kill you.
那就碰碰运气吧
I'll take that chance.
- 博士  - 别傻站着, 快来帮忙
- Doctor!  - Don't just stand there. Come and help.
博士跑掉了, 你的军队失败了
The Doctor is free. Your troopers have failed.
更重要的是, 你的Dalek又在哪里
More to the point, where were your Daleks?
我是Lytton, 呼叫特别行动小组
This is Lytton. Call out my Special Guard.
博士, 你看, 我们应该离开这里
Doctor, look. We should get out of here.
快, 快来
Quickly! Come on.
Lytton太强大了, 他的意识能抵制我们的控制
Lytton grows too arrogant. His mind resists our control.
一有合适的机会就杀了他
He must be exterminated as soon as
it is convenient to the Daleks.
Davros控制了两个Dalek
Davros has control of two Daleks.
他们在接待处, 想要进入博士的Tardis
They are in the reception area,
attempting to enter the Doctor's Tardis.
- 必须杀了他们 - 立刻
- You must exterminate them. - At once.
你也要毁掉Davros
You must also destroy Davros.
他不可靠
He is unreliable.
去, 把病毒释放到Dalek飞船上
Go. Release the virus in the Dalek ship.
Davros的Dalek
Davros's Daleks?
毁掉它们, 这是Dalek元首的命令
Destroy them. The Supreme Dalek's order.
Tardis不在这一层上, 我们去其它地方寻找
The Tardis is not on this level. We must search elsewhere.
动手
Now!
在你后面
Behind you!
隐蔽!
Take cover!
准备降落
We are ready to descend.
继续, 消灭一切
Proceed. Everything must be exterminated,
包括Lytton和他的部队
including Lytton and his troopers.
遵命
We obey.
停下
Stop
消灭
Exterminate
我们一定要找到Tardis, 那是我们的终极目标
We must find the Tardis. That is our prime mission.
我们必须服从Davros
We must obey Davros.
- 怎么了 - 我们遇袭了
- What is happening?
- We are being attacked.
Dalek元首想毁掉我们
The Supreme Dalek wishes us destroyed.
入侵的Dalek必须被消灭
The invading Daleks must be exterminated.
Daleks到自毁系统控制室
Daleks, to the self-destruct chamber.
有敌人闯入. 紧急情况. 紧急情况
A hostile has broken in. Emergency Emergency
必须阻止他
He must be stopped.
找出叛徒 Dalek的敌人必须要被毁掉
We must find the traitors.
The enemy of the Daleks must be destroyed.
我们不是叛徒, 我们服务于我们的创造者 Davros
We are not traitors. We serve our creator, Davros.
Dalek元首是你们的统治者, 任何时候都要服从于他
The Supreme Dalek is your ruler.
He must be obeyed at all times.
- Davros必须得尊重  - 他必须被消灭
- Davros must be honoured.
- He must be exterminated.
什么都不能干扰Dalek的使命
Nothing must interfere the true destiny of the Daleks
你必须被消灭, 消灭!
You must be exterminated. Exterminated
消灭
Exterminated
- 博士  - 干得好
- Doctor!  - Well done.
她想打开那收集器
She's been trying to open the cylinder.
我担心如果她不小心放出病毒的话，就会引发传染
I warned her she could start an epidemic
if she released the virus.
病毒只对Dalek有效, 它完成任务后就会死
The virus is only partial to Dalek.
It would die once it’s doneits work.
下一层情况怎么样了
What's happening on the next floor?
大餐已经为我们的朋友准备好了
Lunch has arrived for our friends here.
现在麻烦是Dalek的了
Now for the Daleks.
我没有召唤你们的协助
I did not summon your assistance.
我们来这儿是为了结果你的
We are here to exterminate you.
- 谁下的命令 - Dalek元首
- By whose order? - The Supreme Dalek.
消灭我 你不过是白白送命罢了
Exterminate me, and you abandon your lives without purpose.
加入到我的队伍 我会让你成为宇宙的统治者
Join me, and I will make you rulers of the universe!
发生故障了
Malfunction
- 紧急情况  - 发生故障了
- EmergencyI - MalfunctionI
你命休矣
Your lives are over!
系统错误
System failureI
开门
Open the doors.
怎么了 我看不到
What is happening? I cannot see.
- 我看不到了, 视力受损  - 紧急情况
- I cannot see. My vision is impaired
- Emergency
他们要死了
They are dying.
你也逃不掉
And so are you.
- 我看不到  - 紧急情况! 紧急情况!
- I cannot see
- Emergency! Emergency!
Dalek们死掉了
The Daleks are dead.
新的Dalek种族万岁
Long live the new Daleks!
噢...
Oh...!
怎么了
What is happening?
不... 不
No...! No!
怎么可能 我...不...是...Dalek
It cannot be! I...am...not...a...Dalek!
我...怎可能...死
I...cannot...die!
我...是...
I...am...
DAAAAVROSSSS
DAAAAVROSSSS!
- 结束了 - 太可怕了
- It's over. - It was horrible.
地球安全了, 至少在Dalek找到解药前是
The Earth is safe, at least until the Daleks
find an antidote for the Movellan virus.
博士快看
Doctor! Look
你没赢, 博士
You have not won, Doctor.
- 你们不能入侵地地球了 - 你一定是忘了 博士
- You won't be able to invade Earth!
- You forget, Doctor.
Dalek不需要入侵
Daleks do not need to invade.
我有复制品
I have my duplicates.
有一些已经被放到这个星球上的战略位置了
Some have already been placed in
strategic positions around the planet.
地球的没落已经为时不远了
The collapse of Earth society will soon occur.
你的复制品们并不稳定，行不通的
Your duplicates aren't stable. It won't work.
Dalek终将胜出
The Daleks will triumph.
我们永不失败
We cannot fail.
Dalek的真实使命是 统治宇宙
The Daleks' true destiny is to rule the universe.
你好, 孩儿们 你们来得正是时候
Hello, boys. Just in time for the fun.
- Dalek飞船被毁了 - 怎么会
- The Dalek ship has been destroyed. - How?
- 空间站上的自毁设备起作用了 - Davros
- The self-destruct device on the station. - Davros?
不,不是...
No, no...
Stien, 我想  最后 他一定做出了选择
Stien, I would think. He must have
finally decided which side he was on.
- 你肯定所有的复制品都不稳定吗 - 嗯 是的
- Are you sure all the duplicates unstable?
- Oh, yes.
是的, 给予一些时间, 他们会摆脱Dalek的控制的
Yes, given time, they will be free of Dalek control.
- 我们要通知地球上的执政者吗 - 啊, 是的, 是的, 要的. 来吧
- Should we inform Earth's authorities?
- Ah, yes. Yes, indeed. Come along.
我不跟你们去了
I'm not coming with you.
- 你说什么  - 我厌倦了
- I beg your pardon?  - I'm tired of it.
- 什么事情  - 今天死了好多人
- What's the matter?
- A lot of good people died today.
- 我很难受  - 你觉得我想让一切发生
- I'm sick of it.  - You think I want this?
不是
No.
我只是在想我没法继续这样下去了
I just don't think I can go on.
- 你想待在地球上 - 我阿姨Vanessa
- You want to stay on Earth?
- My Aunt Vanessa said,
曾在我最初做空姐时说过,
when I became an air stewardess,
- 如果你觉得自己不再喜欢做这个就放弃吧 - Tegan
- if you stop enjoying it, give it up.
-Tegan
这不再有趣了 博士
It's stopped being fun, Doctor!
再见
Goodbye.
Turlough
Turlough?
再见
Goodbye.
我会想你们俩的
I'll miss you both.
- 不 不 不要像这样离开 - 我必须离开 对不起
- No! No, don't leave, not like this.
- I must. I'm sorry.
再见
Goodbye.
真有点儿,呃, 奇怪
It's, uh, strange.
我是因为类似的原因离开Gallifrey的
I left Gallifrey for similar reasons.
我厌倦了他们的生活方式
I'd grown tired of their lifestyle.
看起来我有必要修正我的路线了
It seems I must mend my ways.
来吧
Come on.
（注：Romana I：S16E01 The Ribos Operation登场 S17E01 Destiny of the Daleks重生）
（注：K-9 Mark I：S15E02 Invisible Enemy登场 S15E06 The Invasion of Time和Leela留在Gallifrey
K-9 Mark II：S16E01 The Ribos Operation登场 S18E05 Meglos和RomanaII留在E空间 K-9 Mark III出现于衍生剧中 K-9 Mark IV出现于新版第二季 第四季和衍生剧莎拉简大冒险）
（注：Harry Sullivan：S12E01 Robot登场 S13E01 Terror of the Zygons离开）
（注：第四任博士：
S12E01 Robot重生后上演换衣秀
S18E07 Logopolis中为阻止法师的阴谋而摔死）
（注：第三任博士：S07E01 Spearhead from Space登场 S11E05 Planet of the Spiders重生）
（注：第三任博士：
S07E01 Spearhead from Space登场
S11E05 Planet of the Spiders重生）